Guide to the Metropolitan Council on Housing Records TAM.173
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Metropolitan Council on Housing Records
1939-2014
1959-1995
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.)
Laurie, Jenny
Benjamin, Jaron
TAM.173
70 Linear Feet in 64 record cartons, 3 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes, and 3 oversize folders
The Metropolitan Council on Housing Records (dates 1949-2014) contain correspondence, board meeting minutes, press releases, reports, printed ephemera, government documents, and audio and video recording related to the organizing efforts of the Metropolitan Council on Housing (MCH). The Metropolitan Council on Housing is a membership organization for New York City tenants that focuses on expanding affordable housing and protecting tenants' rights. The organization was formed in 1959 by several labor and housing rights activists, including longtime MCH leaders Jane Benedict and Esther Rand. The collection contains internal records and published materials documenting lobbying campaigns and demonstrations organized by the MCH to promote affordable housing in New York City.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Metropolitan Council on Housing in 1995. Additional materials were donated in 2002, 2008, and 2014. The accession numbers related to these gifts are 1995.013 and 2014.151.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into seven series by record type or date of accretion. Series I: Administrative Files and Series II: Subject Files have grouped records by file type and arranged materials within series alphabetically. Materials in Series III: 2002 through 2007 Accretions, Series V: 2014 Accretion, and Series VI: Audio have received either folder or box-level description and have not been arranged. Materials in Series IV: 2008 Accretion are described at the folder-level and arranged alphabetically within each box.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Metropolitan Council on Housing is non-profit tenant organization that focuses on expanding affordable housing in New York City. The organization was formed in 1959 by a group of labor and housing rights activists, including longtime MCH leaders Jane Benedict and Esther Rand. MCH has fought for increased public housing, the maintenance of rent control, and other housing priorities, using a variety of tactics, including rent strikes and lobbying. MCH is a membership organization, and also has chapters based on buildings. MCH publishes The Tenant/Inquilino and hosts a radio program on WBAI, "Listen to Housing Notebook." The organization's website is: http://www.metcouncil.net/ (accessed June 18, 2007).
Sources:
Ronald Lawson, ed. The Tenant Movement in New York City, 1904-1984(New Brunswick, N.J.: Rutgers University Press, 1986).
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Eastside Tenants Council Records (TAM 253) Cooper Square Committee Records (356)
Scope and Content Note
The Metropolitan Council on Housing Records (dates 1949-2014) contain correspondence, board meeting minutes, press releases, reports, printed ephemera, government documents, and audio and video recording related to the organizing efforts of the Metropolitan Council on Housing (MCR). The first two series of the collection consist of subject and administrative files created by the organization. Administrative files include executive board minutes, programs and ephemera from annual conferences, and records related to MCH's involvement in rent law reforms. Subject files contain records related to specific lobbying campaigns of MCH including rent control and stabilization, public housing, and the Mitchell-Lama housing program.
Subsequent accretions donated between 2002 and 2014 include additional administrative files, ephemera, photographs, newspaper clippings, and periodicals. These files primarily relate to MCH lobbying campaigns and tenants' rights demonstrations. They include correspondence and administrative files related to MCH's work with other housing rights organizations in the city including the Cooper Square Committee, East Side Tenants Council, and the Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association. The collection contains several boxes of audio recordings including, which predominantly consist of recordings for MCH's radio program on WBLS Radio, "Tenants' Fight for Survival." Also included among these materials are copies of MCH's newspaper Tenant, from 1971 to 2014.
The collection also includes captures of the Metropolitan Council on Housing's website beginning in 2009.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Printed ephemera.; Reports.; Community organization -- New York (State) -- New York; Press releases.; Public housing -- New York (State) -- New York; Housing -- New York (State) -- New York; Squatters -- New York (State) -- New York; Rent strikes -- New York (State) -- New York; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government -- 1951-; Rent control -- New York (State) -- New York; Correspondence.; Municipal government records; Clippings (information artifacts); Minutes (administrative records); Government records; Landlord and tenant -- New York (State) -- New York; State government records; National Tenants Organization; Cooper Square Committee; Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.). Community Improvement Fund; Morningsiders United; East Side Tenants Council; Goldin, Frances; Benedict, Jane; Rand, Esther; Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association (New York, N.Y.); Laurie, Jenny; Benjamin, Jaron
- Series I: Administrative Files, 1957-1992; 85526; 9 Linear Feet
  Scope and Content Note
  This series includes executive board minutes, documents relating to MCH's workshops, its annual assemblies and conferences, and to the MCH Community Improvement Fund, files relating to housing code enforcement and fuel cost pass-along, and queries from tenants and tenant groups.
  - Anti-Eviction Committee: MCH committee, undated; 85693 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Architects' Renewal Committee in Harlem (ARCH), MCH part of, undated; 85692 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Metropolitan Council on Housing Correspondences, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Assembly: MCH's annual assemblies, 1967-1988; 85691 (Box 1, Folder 5-7, Box 69, Folder 1-5)
  - DELETE - Assembly: MCH's annual assemblies, 1967-1988; 85690 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - DELETE - Assembly: MCH's annual assemblies, 1967-1988; 85689 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - DELETE - Assembly: MCH's annual assemblies, 1967-1988; 85688 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Benedict, Jane, undated; 85687 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Black Panthers: MCH's work for BPP, undated; 85686 (Box 69, Folder 7-8)
  - Borglum, Helen: Lawsuit: J. Benedict vs. Helen Borglum, undated; 85685 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Branch Information Bulletin, undated; 85684 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Freedom Democratic Movement: MCH's work for Major Owens' City Council campaign 1965, 85683 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Build Public Housing Committee: MCH committee to get public housing built on Rupert Brewery site, 1969; 85682 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Cadman Plaza: MCH's work to get public housing built on Cadman Plaza site 1963, 85681 (Box 70, Folder 3-4)
  - Committee Against Rent Increase Pass-alongs (CARIP): MCH-initiated coalition against rent increase pass-alongs, from 1981; includes papers from lawsuit against Rent Guidelines board, 85680 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Citywide Action Committee Against Homeless: MCH initiated coalition against warehousing, 1990; 85679 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The City-Wide Council For Better Housing: precursor to MCH initiated by MCH founding organizations, 1957; 85678 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - City-Wide Tenants United: MCH initiated coalition, 1976?; 85677 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Code Enforcement: MCH's work on rent increases and code enforcement, 1963-1970; 85676 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Code Enforcement: MCH's work on rent increases and code enforcement, 1963-1970; 85675 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Code Enforcement: MCH's work on rent increases and code enforcement, 1963-1970; 85674 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Code Enforcement: MCH's work on rent increases and code enforcement, 1963-1970; 85673 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Committee To Save Our City's Homes: chaired by Jane Benedict; coalition against demolition, 1962; 85672 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978; 85671 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978; 85670 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978; 85669 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978; 85668 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978; 85667 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978; 85666 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978; 85665 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1962-1978; 85664 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences (NOTE: there are five additional folders on annual conferences in this box), 1962-1978; 85663 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1961-1962; 85662 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Conference: MCH's annual conferences, 1961-1962; 85661 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Constitution Structure: MCH's constitution, adopted 1967, 85660 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Contracts: MCH's work on a model union-like contract for tenants, undated; 85659 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Convention 1983: MCH's 1983 convention, 85658 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cooper Square: MCH's work on alternative plan for Cooper Square site, 1965-1985; 85657 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cooper Square: MCH's work on alternative plan for Cooper Square site, 1965-1985; 85656 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cooper Square: MCH's work on alternative plan for Cooper Square site, 1965-1985; 85655 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cooper Square Community Development Committee: MCH's 1965 annual conference on Cooper Square site, 85654 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Court Cases: Amicus brief for MCH in Park West Village Associates vs Abrams, 1985; 85653 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Courtroom Committee: List of members, 1971; 85652 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Emergency Tenants Protection Act: MCH's work around this legislation, 1974; 85651 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Emergency Tenants Protection Act: MCH's work around this legislation, 1974; 85650 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984; 85649 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984; 85648 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984; 85647 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984; 85646 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984; 85645 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984; 85644 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Executive Board, 1973-1984; 85643 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972; 85642 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972; 85641 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972; 85640 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972; 85639 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972; 85638 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board, 1959-1972; 85637 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Eyedent MCH amicus brief in demolition case, 1979; 85636 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Federation Of NY Tenant Organizations, 1971; 85635 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989; 85634 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989; 85633 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989; 85632 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989; 85631 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989; 85630 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989; 85629 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989; 85628 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989; 85627 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Flynn-Dearie, 1977-1989; 85626 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Foundation #2: Met Council Tenant Foundation, Inc, 1972; 85625 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Foundation #1: Met Council Community Improvement Fund, Inc.and Metropolitan Council Tenants Defense and Education Fund, Inc., 1966-1971; 85624 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Foundation minutes and membership, undated; 85623 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Foundation - Decent Housing For New York's People booklet, undated; 85622 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Foundation - Lindsey's Rent Increase Plan booklet, undated; 85621 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fraud booklet published by MCH, 1970; 85620 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated; 85619 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated; 85618 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated; 85617 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated; 85616 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fuel Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, undated; 85615 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fund-Raising: Various MCH events, undated; 85614 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Heat (through 1981) MCH work on heat laws and enforcement, 85613 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - HRM: MCH's work against city program, 1968; 85612 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Joseph Hyler vice-chair of MCH, undated; 85611 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Independent Action Committee - MCH involved, undated; 85610 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - IN REM Organizational MCH's in rem committee, 1979-1981; 85609 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Invitations from other institutions (speaking), undated; 85608 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Kleiger Decision MCH's motion to intervene - HAD vs. CHIP, 1975; 85607 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Labor Cost Repeal Law MCH as party in lawsuit via CARIP, 1978; 85606 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Labor Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, 1970-1975; 85605 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Labor Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, 1970-1975; 85604 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Labor Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, 1970-1975; 85603 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Labor Cost Passalong: MCH's work against this rent increase program, 1970-1975; 85602 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Law Committee, 1971; 85601 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Law suits: Various, mid-80s, MCH party in, 1980s; 85600 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Leaflet originals, undated; 85599 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Membership, undated; 85598 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Membership, undated; 85597 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Membership, undated; 85596 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Membership, undated; 85595 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Membership Meeting, 1967; 85594 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Membership Ocean-Kings, 1973; 85593 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated; 85592 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated; 85591 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated; 85590 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated; 85589 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - MCH Community Improvement Fund, undated; 85588 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - MCH: General Publicity, undated; 85587 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - MCH: General Publicity, undated; 85586 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - MCH: Evaluation, 1959-1965; 85585 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - MCH: Policy and statements, undated; 85584 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Buildings, undated; 85583 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Nominations Committee, 1983; 85582 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Nominations Committee, 1983; 85581 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Nominations, 1982; 85580 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Vici O'Mara - MCH board member, undated; 85579 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Organizing Committee 1977-current, 85578 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Organizer, The: MCH internal newsletter, undated; 85577 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Organizing handbook (MCH publication), 1971-1973; 85576 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Organizing handbook (MCH publication), 1971-1973; 85575 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Political Action, undated; 85574 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - People Outraged With Energy Rates (POWER): MCH involved, undated; 85573 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Press MCH op-eds, etc, undated; 85572 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Public Housing Committee, undated; 85571 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Public housing: 1967 Conference, 85570 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Public housing: Massive Public Housing, undated; 85569 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Public housing: MCH Program, undated; 85568 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Publicity: Clippings mentioning MCH, undated; 85567 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Public ownership, undated; 85566 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Queries, undated; 85565 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Queries, undated; 85564 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Queries, undated; 85563 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Queries, undated; 85562 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Queries, undated; 85561 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Queries, undated; 85560 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Queries, undated; 85559 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Queries, undated; 85558 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Queries, undated; 85557 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Queries, undated; 85556 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Queries, undated; 85555 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Queries, undated; 85554 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Esther Rand (Memorial Meeting), undated; 85553 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Esther Rand, undated; 85552 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Jack Rand, undated; 85551 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rents into Repairs (see also Foundation), undated; 85550 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Songs, undated; 85549 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Spanish Organizing Committee, undated; 85548 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - William Stanley, undated; 85547 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Tenants, you are not alone, undated; 85546 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Times Square, 1986-1992; 85545 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Times Square Hotel #1, undated; 85544 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Times Square Hotel #2, undated; 85543 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 25th Anniversary, undated; 85542 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Vacant Land Survey #1, undated; 85541 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Vacant Land Survey #2, undated; 85540 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - WBLS- Radio, undated; 85539 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - WBAI, undated; 85538 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - We Won't Move Committee (102nd St.- Don Erwin et. 21), undated; 85537 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - What is the Metropolitan Council on Housing? And similar pamphlets, undated; 85536 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Workshops, 1989; 85535 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Workshops, 1988; 85534 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Workshops, 1987; 85533 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Workshops, 1973; 85532 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Workshop Materials June 26, 1971-News Coverage #1, 85531 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Workshop Materials June 26, 1971- News Coverage #2, 85530 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Workshops: MCH, undated; 85529 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Your Home Is Your Hassle, undated; 85528 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Youth Project, undated; 85527 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1961-1992; 85275; 14 Linear Feet
  This series contains files relating to Columbia University and its relations with Morningsiders United, Mitchell-Lama and other public housing, the National Tenants Organization, New York State housing legislation and related lobbying efforts, rent control and rent stabilization, the Unity Party, Tenant Unity Day, urban renewal, and warehousing.
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85525 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85524 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85523 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85522 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85521 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85520 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85519 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85518 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85517 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85516 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85515 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85514 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85513 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85512 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85511 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85510 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85509 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Albany, 1976-1989; 85508 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Allerton Coops, undated; 85507 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Columbia Tenants Union, undated; 85506 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Columbia Tenants Union, undated; 85505 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Columbia University: includes Morningsiders United, undated; 85504 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University: includes Morningsiders United, undated; 85503 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Columbia University: includes Morningsiders United, undated; 85502 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Columbia University: includes Morningsiders United, undated; 85501 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Greater Flushing Tenants Council, undated; 85500 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Homefront, undated; 85499 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hotels, undated; 85498 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hotels, undated; 85497 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Housing For All, undated; 85496 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Housing Now, undated; 85495 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Listener's Action (later called Housing Now), undated; 85494 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988; 85493 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988; 85492 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988; 85491 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988; 85490 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988; 85489 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988; 85488 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988; 85487 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Legislation, 1974-1988; 85486 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85485 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85484 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85483 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85482 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85481 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85480 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85479 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85478 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85477 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85476 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85475 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85474 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85473 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Legislation, 1962-1974; 85472 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Joseph Mauri, undated; 85471 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982; 85470 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982; 85469 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982; 85468 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Mitchell-Lama: includes files on developments, 1976-1982; 85467 (Box 13, Folder 5)